**Aman Kanojia** | North Harrow, London, UK | <u>aman22kanojia@gmail.com</u> | +44 20 3290 1553 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/aman-kanojia22/ |

### **PERSONAL STATEMENT**

Graduate Data Scientist with a Master's in Big Data Science and a strong background in python development, statistical modelling, machine learning, and predictive analytics. Possesses 1+ year of industry experience and stellar academic record (**Distinction**), seeking a role to apply advanced skills in software development industry with proficiency in Al/ML algorithms involving tasks to optimize operations, mitigate risks, drive strategic business decisions to overcome challenges.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Production Team Member

(Nov 2023-May 2023)

#### DrugsRus, London

- Spearheaded initiatives to optimize production processes at DrugsRus, resulting in a remarkable 33%
   reduction in overall production time, significantly delivering operational efficiency and cost-effectiveness.
- Played a pivotal role in maintaining DrugsRus's competitive edge in the pharmaceutical industry, contributing
  to the timely delivery of high-quality medications which impact the market, in alignment with industry leaders
  such as AstraZeneca and Novo Nordisk.
- Python Developer Trainee

## **Bofikre (E-commerce store)**

(June 2021-June 2022)

- Spearheaded backend development for Bofikre's e-commerce platform using Python and Django, managing operations for 10,000+ daily active users and handling 5,000+ concurrent requests during peak periods.
- Engineered RESTful APIs and integrated multiple payment gateways, facilitating finance in online transactions and reducing checkout abandonment by 15%.
- Intern (June 2020-Dec 2020)

EI Systems (IIT BHU)

- Developed machine learning algorithms and models during an internship at El Systems, leveraging Python, TensorFlow, and scikit-learn to enhance predictive analytics capabilities and optimize decision-making processes exploring huge datasets.
- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team to research and implement innovative machine learning solutions, contributing to the advancement of AI-driven technologies in areas such as natural language processing, computer vision, and predictive maintenance.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Database: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Programming Languages: Python and C++

Data analysis: Python (Seaborn, NumPy, SciPy)

- Data Science: Machine Learning, Statistics, Mathematics, Deep Learning
- Web Dev: HTML/CSS, Streamlit and Django
- Deep Learning: **Pandas**, TensorFlow and Keras (Frameworks).
- Cloud Computing: AWS

Soft-skills: Analytical Skills, Problem Solving skills, Excellent Communication skills and Presentation skills

# **EDUCATION**

Queen Mary University of London, London (Part of Prestigious Rusell Group) (2022-2023)
 Candidate for MSC in Big Data Science, Secured **Distinction**. (8.0/10.0)

Shri Ram Institute of Technology, RGPV, Jabalpur 2017- 2021)
Candidate for B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering, Secured **Distinction**(9.0/10.0)

.